Hello, have you ever wondered how to prepare for a divorce? Well, I'm Dr. Felicia and I'd like to share a few tips with you.
Preparing for divorce is a very scary and frightening prospect, whether you're the male or the female in the relationship.
One of the things you want to consider, especially if you're the female is that for instance today, most court jurisdictions only allow about three years alimony for rehabilitation.
So, if the partner wanted to go back to school and be career-oriented, that's give them three years time in preparation.
So, that's a pretty frightening prospect in itself.
If you already had a career and you're in a working world, it's not as quite as frightening, but, chances are your assets are pretty well divided, and you're going to need to start to secure some new aspects for yourself.
You want to decide if keeping the house is in your best interest or perhaps the expenses to run the house are just so expensive, it's not worth it.
You may wish to downsize and put yourself into a situation where you can readily afford it on one person's pay.
The other thing that you want to prepare for is housing.
If you have children, you need to prepare, if you're going to have to move and assign them into new schools, get them registered.
You may need to actually enlist family support for child care.
You may need to get all kinds of clothing sorted out, in terms of who keeps what, belongings and personal belongings in the house, who keeps what.
And if you are the caretaker of the children, you obviously need more than the party who's going to leave without the children.
In either case, I wish you good luck.
And remember it's how to prepare and survive for divorce is never easy.
Good luck, Dr. Felicia, goodbye.